Selden Warner Papers, ca. 1707-1890
Connecticut Historical Society
Selden Warner Papers
ca. 1707-1890
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Warner, Selden
0.6 linear feet (1.5 boxes)
Biographical Sketch
Selden Warner, son of Jonathan and Elizabeth Selden Warner, was born on October 20, 1760 in Hadlyme, CT. He died of paralysis at age 82 in Hadlyme, CT on March 1, 1843. Selden Warner was a farmer in his hometown and he graduated from Yale College in 1782. Mr. Warner was living in New London County at the time of the 1790 Census with his wife and two sons. He also represented his town several times in the State Legislature. Based on court documents within the collection, records indicate that a Selden Warner was a Justice of the Peace. While in Hadlyme, Mr. Warner and his wife were members of the Congregational Church. He served as Deacon at this church until 1833, when he asked to be removed from further duty. In addition, Selden Warner was a captain in the 33rd Regiment, 3rd Brigade, Connecticut Militia around 1799. He married his second cousin Dorothy Selden on June 5, 1788. Dorothy Selden was born on December 26, 1766 and she died on August 19, 1825. She was a daughter of Col. Samuel and Elizabeth (Ely) Selden, of Hadlyme, CT.
Records indicated that there may have been a second marriage of Selden Warner, who lived in Lyme, CT to Elizabeth Spencer on January 4, 1827.
The births of Selden Warner’s first six children were recorded in the town records of Lyme, CT. 1) Selden Warner, Jr. (name changed to Samuel Selden Warner) born on March 15, 1789; married Abby Champlin; after Abby he married Azubah Tully. 2) Andrew Ferdinando Warner was born on December 29, 1790; he married Lucinthia Cone. 3) Joseph Warner born on December 3, 1792; he married Mary Ann Holmes. 4) Richard Warner was born on October 19, 1794; he married twice, Mary Millicent Gilbert and Mary Gaylord. 5) William Henry Warner was born February 18, 1797; he married Sarah Canfield. 6) Mathew Griswold Warner born on March 6, 1799; he married Lucretia Hubbard Loomis. 7) Mary Warner was born on January 17, 1801 and she died in Hadlyme on August 10, 1825. Mary was a member of the Congregational Church in 1822. 8) Elizabeth Warner was born on April 20, 1803 and she died in Hadlyme on September 15, 1825. 9) Jonathan Trumbull Warner was born on November 20, 1807; he married Anita Gale.
Scope and Content
The collection was given to the Connecticut Historical Society by Mr. Hayden R. Lathrop of Hartford, Connecticut. It consists of family and business letters, records of shad fishing on the Connecticut River (1805-1869), legal documents, and Warner family accounts (1803-1869). The fishing books itemize the number of fish caught by several individuals who probably worked for Selden Warner. The fishing records also indicate how much catch was delivered to various fish markets, including Fulton Fish Market in New York City. Financial records include bills, receipts, and accounts, including accounts with the proprietors of the Cover Fishery and the North Minorca Fishing Company.
The Selden Warner court papers are of cases over which Mr. Warner presided as Justice of the Peace. The severity of the crimes varies in scope from debts owed to physical violence. In some contract cases, the defendant is unable to pay for their usage of a particular parcel of land and they have to appear in front of Selden Warner. The bulk of the materials are writs of attachment, summons, and jury summons. Land contracts and deeds are for properties owned in Lyme and East Haddam, Connecticut.
Nancy W. Ely received some letters within collection. Nancy W. Ely is a relative of Elizabeth Ely, daughter of Richard Ely and Elizabeth Peck. She was Selden Warner’s sister-in-law. The letters to Nancy W. Ely are of a business nature--accounts and financial transactions.
A folder of assorted Selden Warner legal documents include an agreement to build a pier in Lyme in order to catch fish, the minutes of the North Minorca Fishing Company, Joseph Warner’s deed, and a lease.
In a final folder are documents that appear unrelated to the Warner family. They include a composition by Mar Ann Ely, anonymous compositions, what appears to be a sermon, school exercises and a commonplace book.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Warner, Selden, 1760-1843.; Ely, Nancy W.
Subjects
Cove Fishery.; North Minorca Fishing Co.; Fishing --Connecticut --Hadlyme.; Justices of the peace --Connecticut --Hadlyme.; Shad fishing --Connecticut --Hadlyme.
Contents:
- Papers
  - Selden Warner letters, 1795-1840 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Warner Estate, 1707-1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Extended Family letters, 1819-1841 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financials, 1784-1886 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fishing Records, 1784-1823 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fishing accounts, 1803-1825 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Selden Warner court papers, 1789-1816 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Court Summons, 1797-1816 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Land contacts, mortgages, deeds, 1784-1884 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nancy W. Ely letters, 1854-1890 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Assorted legal papers, 1781-1827 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photograph, compositions, sermon, commonplace book and school exercise booklet, and random letters, 1818-1831 (Box 2, Folder 4)